Finding Aid for the Ojai Music Festival Records PASC-M.0277
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Ojai Clippings, 1940s-1980s; Series 11.
  - OFCOE 1992/93 Press Clippings, 1992-1993; papers (Box 62, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of press clippings and materials related to OFCOE (Ojai Festival Community Outreach and Education).
  - Ojai Festival 1954, 1959, programs and photographs (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Program guides to the 1954 Ojai Festival; laminated and original photo of three performers; issue of Ojai Valley Life May 1959; program for 1959 Festival
  - Ojai Press 1950s, newspaper clippings and mimeographs of news (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Press releases and news clippings regarding Ojai Festivals during the 1950's
  - Ojai Press 1960s-I, newspaper and magazine clippings, photocopies (Box 13, Folder 4)
    news clippings regarding Ojai Festivals during the 1960's
  - Ojai Press 1960s-II, newspaper and magazine clippings, photocopies (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Ojai Press 1970s, news clippings, memos and mimeographs (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Materials related to the background and history of the Ojai Festival, during the 1970's
  - Ojai Press 1980s, news clippings, memos and mimeographs (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Materials related to the background and history of the Ojai Festival, during the 1980's
  - Ojai Press 1990s, Press kit (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Materials related to the background and history of the Ojai Festival, during the 1990's
  - Ojai Program, 1950,1959; papers (Box 73, Folder 2)
    Photocopies of Festival programs from 1950 and 1959.
  - Other music festivals, 1980s; newspaper clippings (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Clippings regarding music festivals other than Ojai, such as Cabrillo.
  - Other Music Festivals Press Folder 2, 1960s-1970s; news clippings (Box 36, Folder 2)
    related to music festivals other than Ojai
  - Other Music Festivals Press Folder 1, 1960s-1970s; news clippings (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Outreach and Education, 1992-1993; papers (Box 62, Folder 1)
    Press releases and correspondence related to Ojai's Outreach and Education initiatives.
  - Post Festival Reviews, 1993; papers (Box 59, Folder 5)
    Photocopies of press clippings of the 1993 Festival.
  - Press, 1992-1993; papers (Box 59, Folder 9)
    Press clippings, releases, and correspondence with members of the press.
  - Press 1980s, Photocopied news clippings (Box 41, Folder 1)
    Festival press from the 1980's, when Boulez was condutor/director.
  - Press clippings, 1951, 1952,1982; news clippings on construction paper (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Southern California-based news clippings
    All clippings are from 1951-52 with exception of Ojai Valley News "panorama" section from June 2, 1982
  - Press Contact info, 1992; papers (Box 85, Folder 4)
    Mailing and contact info for various members of the press; some press releases
  - Press photos, 1988; photographs, slides, negatives (Box 42, Folder 13)
    Photographs: John Adams, Rosemary Clooney, etc.
  - Press releases and clippings, 1990-1992; papers (Box 85, Folder 2)
    Copies of news articles and press releases
  - Press releases and contract info, 1990-1996; papers, photographs (Box 42, Folder 12)
    Press releases, programs, brochures and photographs related to seasons between 1990 and 1996.
  - Press releases 1993 Festival, papers (Box 59, Folder 8)
    Press releases and brochures about Festival artists, eg Kronos Quartet.
  - Press Reviews 1992-93, 1992-1993; papers (Box 59, Folder 7)
    Photocopies of Festival press
  - San Francisco Contemporary Music Players, 1989-1990; Poster/tour calendar (Box 40, Folder 4)
    Promotional poster for the SFCMP, whose 1989-90 season was their 15th.
  - Clippings-- Scrapbooks, Subseries 1.
    - 1953 Scrapbook, newspaper clippings in scrapbook (Box 9, Folder 1)
      News clippings for 1953 Ojai Festival.
      Some clippings are missing; many are marked with pencil and some are loose from page.
    - 1955 Scrapbook, 1954-1955; newspaper clippings in scrapbook (Box 4, Folder 1)
      News clippings for 1955 Ojai Festival.
      Cover of scrapbook is not attached.
    - 1958 Scrapbook, newspaper clippings in scrapbook (Box 9, Folder 2)
      News clippings for 1958 Ojai Festival.
      Covers of book are unattached. Most clippings have pencil markings on them.
    - 1960 Scrapbook, 1959-1960; newspaper clippings in scrapbook (Box 4, Folder 2)
      News clippings for 1960 Ojai Festival.
      Cover of scrapbook is not attached. There is a blue notecard with book that says: "1960 (not programs) copied" Blue pencil marks on many of the clippings
    - 1961 Scrapbook, 1960-61; Scrapbook with news clippings (Box 21, Folder 5)
      Clippings and programs relevant to 1961 season, in which Lukas Foss was conductor.
      Many news clippings marked with pencil and/or tape.
    - 1962 Scrapbook, Bound press clippings (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Scrapbook with news clippings from the 1962 Festival.
    - 1963 Scrapbook, Scrapbook with news clippings (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Clippings, photographs and programs relevant to 1963 season, in which Lukas Foss was conductor.
    - 1964 Scrapbook, newspaper clippings in scrapbook (Box 10, Folder 1)
      News clippings for 1964 Ojai Festival.
      Covers are not attached to scrapbook. Most clippings have pencil markings on them.
    - 1965 Scrapbook, 1964-65; Scrapbook of articles from 1964-65 festivals (Box 24, Folder 9)
      Loose scrapbook pages with annotated articles
      Book is bound but pages within it are loose
    - 1966 Scrapbook, newspaper clippings in scrapbook (Box 10, Folder 2)
      News clippings for 1966 Ojai Festival.
      Front cover not attached to scrapbook and pages are not attached. Most clippings have pencil markings on them.
    - 1967 Scrapbook, Scrapbook with news clippings (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Clippings and programs relevant to 1967 season, in which Pierre Boulez was conductor.
      Scrapbook is not bound--covers and individual sheets are not together. Many clippings have pencil markings on them
    - 1969 Scrapbook, Scrapbook with news clippings (Box 21, Folder 3)
      Clippings, photographs and programs relevant to 1969 season, in which Michael Tilson Thomas was conductor.
      Some of the sheets are not bound to the scrapbook.
    - 1980 Scrapbook, 1979-1980; Scrapbook of articles from 1979-80 festivals (Box 24, Folder 10)
      Scrapbook with annotated articles
      Book is bound and pages are attached. Program glued to inside cover of front.
    - 1981 Scrapbook, Scrapbook (Box 46, Folder 3)
      News clippings and programs from 1981 season.
      Binding is intact and there are no plastic coverings.
    - 1985 Scrapbook, 1984-1985; Scrapbook (Box 46, Folder 4)
      Press clippings related to 1985 Season.
      Binding is intact. Some clippings are loose. No plastic sheets.
    - 1987 Scrapbook, Photo album (Box 46, Folder 2)
      News clippings from the 1987 Season.
      Binding is missing and several clippings are loose from sticky backing.
    - 1988 Scrapbook, Clippings in scrapbook pages (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Scrapbook pages held together with binder clip. No binding.
      All pages relevant to 1988 Festival (Nicholas McGegan, music director). Many clippings have pencil/pen markings on them.
    - 1989 Scrapbook, loose clippings and pages from scrapbook (Box 22, Folder 2)
      articles, programs and reviews relevant to 1989 Ojai Festival (Boulez, conductor)
      no book, just individual pages from scrapbook, held together with binder clips
    - 1994 Scrapbook, Clippings in scrapbook pages (Box 22, Folder 5)
      All pages relevant to 1994 Festival (Michael Tilson Thomas, conductor), with one page from 1984.
      Scrapbook pages held together with rings.
  - Clippings-- Loose, Subseries 2.
    - 1949 Festival Clippings, Clippings, photographs, scrapbook pages (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1959 Festival.
      Left in original order.
    - 1950 Festival Original News Clips, Clippings (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1950 Festival.
      Many clippings have been glued to cardboard or paperboard.
    - 1951 Festival clippings, Clippings, scrapbook pages (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1951 Festival.
    - 1954 Festival clippings, Clippings, scrapbook pages (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1954 Festival.
    - 1954 Festival Clippings, Clippings, scrapbook pages (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - 1956 Festival Clippings, Clippings, scrapbook pages (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1956 Festival.
    - 1956, 1957 Festival clippings, Clippings, scrapbook pages (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1956, 1957 Festivals.
    - 1957 Festival clippings, Clippings, scrapbook pages (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1957 Festival.
    - 1959 Festival Clippings, Clippings, photographs, scrapbook pages (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 1968 Festival Clippings, Clippings, scrapbook pages, photographs (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Loose scrapbook pages and clippings related to 1968 Festival.
    - 1986 Festival Clippings, news clippings and scrapbook excerpts (Box 24, Folder 1)
      News articles and information glued onto sheets and scrapbook pages.
    - 1988 Festival Clippings, loose clippings (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Loose clippings and one scrapbook page.
    - 1989 Festival Clippings, Photocopied news clippings (Box 41, Folder 6)
      Related to 1989 Festival.
    - 1989 Scrapbook II, loose clippings and pages from scrapbook (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Includes articles, programs and reviews relevant to 1989 Ojai Festival (Boulez, conductor).
      Loose scrapbook pages held together with binder clips.
    - Background materials Ojai I, 1940's-1950's; news clippings, memos and mimeographs (Box 13, Folder 7)
      Materials related to the background and history of the Ojai Festival, through the 1950's
    - Background materials Ojai II, 1960's; news clippings, memos and mimeographs (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Materials related to the background and history of the Ojai Festival, during the 1960's
    - Festival Clippings, 1993-1994; news and magazine clippings (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Loose scrapbook pages. Includes: In Style magazine story of benefit at Larry Hagman's house; news clippings from 1992 season.
    - Loose clippings, photographs, 1960s-1980s; news clippings, photographs, photocopies (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Original and photocopied news clippings from the 1980s; photographs from the 1960s and 1970s
      Photographs of Aaron Copland, Pierre Boulez, Kent Nagano
    - Loose scrapbook clippings, 1980s-1990s; papers, news clippings (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Original and photocopied news clippings from various Festivals in the 1980s and 1990s.
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1960's; original and photocopied articles (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Loose news clippings about various Ojai Festivals during the 1960s.
    - Ojai press 1940s, 1949; news clippings (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Unprocessed Materials, Series 12.
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers, 1997-2004 (Box 101)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 102)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 115)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 117)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers, 1997 (Box 118, Copy 2)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 133)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 134)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 135)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 143)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 144)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 145)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 146)
  - Assorted Unprocessed Papers (Box 147)
  - Rolodex (Box 108)
  - Unprocessed financial papers (Box 140)
  - Unprocessed Financial Papers (Box 141)
  - Unprocessed Financial Papers (Box 142)
  - Unprocessed Papers on 1995 Festival (Box 131)
  - Unprocessed Papers on 1995 Festival (Box 132)
  - Unprocessed Papers on 1994 Festival (Box 136)
  - Unprocessed Papers on 1994 Festival (Box 137)
  - Unprocessed Papers on 1994 Festival (Box 138)
  - Unprocessed Papers on 1994 Festival (Box 139)
  - Unprocessed payroll and finances
- Ojai Archives, Series 13.; 1960-1965
  Files designated as "Archives" by the Ojai Festival.
  - Unprocessed Materials (Box 123)
  - Unprocessed Materials (Box 124)
  - Unprocessed Materials (Box 125)
  - Unprocessed Materials (Box 126)